[
  {
    "question": "Which term BEST describes the use of existing images, objects, or materials to create new artworks?",
    "a": "interpretation",
    "b": "recontextualization",
    "c": "assimilation",
    "d": "appropriation",
    "e": "adaptation",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "What role do catadores play in their communities?",
    "a": "maintaining public parks and green spaces",
    "b": "collecting and recycling waste materials",
    "c": "harvesting crops on large-scale farms",
    "d": "creating handmade artisan crafts",
    "e": "organizing cultural events and festivals",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "The conceptual art movement places the most importance on the",
    "a": "materials used to create an artwork",
    "b": "technical skill needed to create an artwork",
    "c": "composition of an artwork",
    "d": "idea behind an artwork",
    "e": "historical context surrounding an artwork",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which photographic process creates precise images on silver-coated plates?",
    "a": "daguerreotype",
    "b": "collodion",
    "c": "ambrotype",
    "d": "albumen",
    "e": "cyanotype",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where does the Documenta exhibition take place?",
    "a": "Valencia, Spain",
    "b": "Milan, Italy",
    "c": "Stockholm, Sweden",
    "d": "São Paulo, Brazil",
    "e": "Kassel, Germany",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "How do Earthworks differ from the larger Land art movement?",
    "a": "Earthworks often require consultation with environmental scientists and researchers.",
    "b": "Earthworks only use natural materials sourced directly from the Earth.",
    "c": "Earthworks are large-scale outdoor installations.",
    "d": "Earthworks often engage with indigenous culture and traditions.",
    "e": "Earthworks rely heavily on audience participation.",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does the environmental justice movement respond to pressing social and ecological issues?",
    "a": "by advocating for equal access to clean resources and environments",
    "b": "by creating educational programs on sustainable living practices",
    "c": "by implementing green infrastructure projects in local communities",
    "d": "by promoting indigenous land rights and sovereignty",
    "e": "by conducting scientific research on the need for sustainability",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "When did the American environmental movement mobilize?",
    "a": "the 1960s",
    "b": "the 1950s",
    "c": "the 1940s",
    "d": "the 1980s",
    "e": "the 1970s",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "How do kinetic artworks engage their audiences?",
    "a": "by incorporating mechanical elements",
    "b": "by collaborating with live performers",
    "c": "by using dynamic color schemes",
    "d": "by employing optical illusions",
    "e": "by including audio elements",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which genre of art emphasized the beauty and grandeur of the natural world?",
    "a": "environmental painting",
    "b": "historical painting",
    "c": "still life painting",
    "d": "portrait painting",
    "e": "landscape painting",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Manifest Destiny was the belief that the United States was destined to",
    "a": "spread democratic values throughout the world",
    "b": "expand westward across the entire North American continent",
    "c": "assert military superiority over indigenous tribes and rival nations",
    "d": "convert local indigenous peoples to Christianity",
    "e": "lay trade routes and transportation networks across the Pacific",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the following features characterize the Minimalist movement EXCEPT",
    "a": "extreme simplicity",
    "b": "dynamic compositions",
    "c": "limited color palettes",
    "d": "emphasized form and space",
    "e": "basic geometric shapes",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who pioneered the concept of Readymades?",
    "a": "Salvador Dalí",
    "b": "Piet Mondrian",
    "c": "Pablo Picasso",
    "d": "Vasily Kandinsky",
    "e": "Marcel Duchamp",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which artistic movement focused on emotion, nature, individualism, and the sublime?",
    "a": "Surrealism",
    "b": "Postmodernism",
    "c": "Abstract Expressionism",
    "d": "Romanticism",
    "e": "Impressionism",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "The term “toxic sublime” is MOST strongly associated with",
    "a": "political corruption and corporate greed",
    "b": "environmental racism and systemic inequality",
    "c": "pollution and environmental degradation",
    "d": "food insecurity and access to limited resources",
    "e": "forced displacement of indigenous peoples",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  }
]